<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indie Comics Group | making and sharing comics </title>
    <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/categories/comics/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2011-12-11 11:30:20 &#43;0200 &#43;0200</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Future of Publishing</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-11-The-Future-of-Publishing/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-11-The-Future-of-Publishing/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_by_ted_bergeron&#34;&gt;By Ted Bergeron&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m trying to imagine what the future of comics will be.
So I&amp;#8217;m trying to create a &#39;blueprint&#39; for making comics so that they still could be printed.
Then take those files and make mobile apps, color e-books, web comics… every method of sharing comics digitally.
The idea is books could be printed, if anyone wanted to pay a lot for one, but mostly they&amp;#8217;d be shared electronically.
I think this would be the most inexpensive method for indie creators to share their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m firmly in the paper book camp.
But I&amp;#8217;m trying to embrace the migration to mostly electronic for comics.
I&amp;#8217;m predicting the future is digital with a handful of lovingly crafted, print-on-demand comics (probably collected works / graphic novels) for collectors that treasure a particular comic book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-quote-left fa-1x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
Howdy, I do think your website may be having internet browser compatibility problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I take a look at your website in Safari, it looks fine but when opening in IE, it has some overlapping issues.
I merely wanted to provide you with a quick heads up!
Besides that, great website!
&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-quote-right fa-1x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;
&amp;#8212; Posted by Mississauga Soccer | August 5&lt;br&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;2013&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reply to this comment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-quote-left fa-1x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll take a look. And thanks for checking out the website.
&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-quote-right fa-1x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;
&amp;#8212; Posted by Ted Bergeron | August 6&lt;br&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;2013&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Way Forward</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-07-The-Way-Forward/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-07-The-Way-Forward/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we all work together we can achieve our dreams.
So step one has to be what are our dreams?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As creators, I think we all want to work on making comics full time.
So my first thought is why don&amp;#8217;t I get a job as a comic book artist?
Well, easier said than done.
So I need to build a portfolio.
Make some comics.
Start showing off my work.
Start knocking on big publisher&amp;#8217;s doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping back I realized that since I was already making comics, just for the fun of it.
I might be able to short cut the process and just publish them myself.
So I started off shrinking down my full size comic book pages to fit into a mini comic book.
5-1/2 x 8-1/2 folded and stapled and &#39;printed&#39; B&amp;amp;W on a photocopier.
That is a fairly simple and inexpensive method of printing a comic book.
And I was able to put my comic book into the reader&amp;#8217;s hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I made my black and white art to the correct size, I can still have it colored and send it of to the printer to have them make some color glossy comic books for me.
I&amp;#8217;d still have to invest my money into printing these, but I&amp;#8217;d have them on hand to sell at conventions or off my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I looked into making a digital copy.
It was fairly easy to make a .PDF file that I could e-mail to people.
And I can make as many copies as I need for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m happy to share what I know with anyone that is making comics.
So I intend to start adding some tutorials in the wiki.
If you&amp;#8217;d like to share your knowledge, please join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Beginning</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-06-The-Beginning/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-06-The-Beginning/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the beginning.
I&amp;#8217;ve created this website with the intention of helping others make comics and share comics.
I teach a making comic books class at my local Community College.
I find that many people have a desire to create stories but not very many people know what all goes into making comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After they&amp;#8217;ve made some comics the next question is usually how do I get published?
Which generally translates into how do I become rich and famous making comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to attempt to answer these questions here and share some guidelines and standards.
Hopefully we will all learn something and together become the largest voice in comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
