<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indie Comics Group | making and sharing comics </title>
    <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/tags/writing/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2016</rights>
    <updated>2013-04-11 11:30:20 &#43;0200 &#43;0200</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Writing for the love of it. #3</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2013-04-11-Writing-for-the-love-of-it-3/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2013 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2013-04-11-Writing-for-the-love-of-it-3/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you&amp;#8217;re reading&amp;#8230;&amp;#8203;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_blog&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing for the love of it is back&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Alverne Ball&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi, Sorry I&amp;#8217;ve been away for a very long time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The truth is my hard drive crashed about a year ago and I lost a lot of info when it came to websites such as this and I couldn&amp;#8217;t for the life of me remember how to navigate back to it.
I know.
It&amp;#8217;s a shame that I relied on technology so much.
But in between that time I had a son, well I didn&amp;#8217;t have it, but you get the idea.
I&amp;#8217;ve also grown as a writer since that time.
I&amp;#8217;ve been published by a few indy imprints such as 133art.com where I&amp;#8217;m working on a mini-series called One Nation about metaphysical super humans and what it means to be a hero in a real world.
I&amp;#8217;m currently also writing a 100+ page graphic novel for a publisher as well as developing several comic book and TV ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The writing never stops.
But enough about me.
Writing for the love of it will be about you, the writer or creator, and how one navigates the uneasy road of creating comics at a professional level.
I&amp;#8217;ll be taking suggestions about topics that you&amp;#8217;d love to hear as well as talking about creating comics from a  writer&amp;#8217;s point of view.
We&amp;#8217;ll deconstruct scripts, talk about what inspires us, and how to use your weaknesses as a writer to your advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I&amp;#8217;ve been away but now I&amp;#8217;m back and I hope that we&amp;#8217;ll both learn something along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alverne&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•Share
•&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 Responses to “Writing for the love of it is back”
1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratz on having a son! And on your writing endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am really interested in your up coming topics. I have been struggling to make comics this past year. I feel that my writing is pretty juvenile. And would really like to improve my story concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;literalblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt; Posted by Ted Bergeron | April 18, 2013, 10:21 pm
Reply to this comment
◦&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tom,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for taking the time to read my post. I&amp;#8217;ll be looking to talk a lot about making comics on a shoestring budget as well as writing them and how to overcome some of the hurdles that we all face as writers. Look for my next post to be sometime next week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;literalblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt; Posted by Alverne | April 19, 2013, 7:42 am
Reply to this comment&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;literalblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;2.&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congrats on having a son. That is always a special moment. Having children definitely makes it a little more difficult to get back into the writing groove. Well it did for me anyways. Good to see you have projects you are working on and judging by the date of the post you have probably already finished some. Anyways I just wanted to say hello. I love the idea of a indie comics group so I wanted to join in. Look forward to chatting again soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;literalblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt; Posted by K.N. Porter | July 18, 2013, 11:45 pm
Reply to this comment
◦&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hi K.N&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the comment. I&amp;#8217;ve been bad about updating my post and yes, I&amp;#8217;ve completed a few books. Having a kid does make it harder to get things done. I&amp;#8217;m going to write a new post after SDCC. Hopefully i can get a post done at least once a month. maybe the internet will keep me honest. Looking forward to talk to you soon about the craft of writing comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;literalblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt; Posted by Alverne Ball | July 19, 2013, 8:06 am
Reply to this comment&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Post a Comment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Name *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;E-mail *&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Website&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;literalblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Notify me of follow-up comments by email.&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;literalblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;Notify me of new posts by email.&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Categories
•Blog (6)
•Publishing (7)
•Techniques (2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages
•About
•Answers
•Archives
•Authors
•Contact
•Join
•Site Map&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Staff&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ted Bergeron Editor&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alverne Ball Author&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Writing for the love of it. #2</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2012-02-14-Writing-for-the-love-of-it-2/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2012 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2012-02-14-Writing-for-the-love-of-it-2/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_blog&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Alverne Ball&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The other day a young creator twittered me a message asking how I started out in making comics.
After relating a story where I tried to learn everything I could about the production of comics before jumping in feet first and learning on the go I came to the idea that this entry should be about how to start making comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;olist arabic&#34;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&#34;arabic&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;#8217;ve got your idea, the job as creator is to either write the tale or find someone that can write it for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nail down the script(s).
Make sure you&amp;#8217;ve got the story down before you move forward with any other aspect of production.
If that means you have to write for a year then do so, but have at most 80-90 % of the story done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find an artist or a writer.
This one depends on what your artistic profession is in the role of the creation of the comic.
Since I&amp;#8217;m a writer I&amp;#8217;ll talk more towards a writer finding an artist.
If you have an idea of the artwork you want for the book then that&amp;#8217;s great!
You&amp;#8217;re ahead of the curve, but if you&amp;#8217;re like me where you have no idea and usually wait for an artist&amp;#8217;s work  to grab you then you should probably have most of the story written.  The reason I&amp;#8217;m adamant about having the story nearly complete is because once you do find the artist you want to work with he/she will ask to see a sample of the writing.  If you, as the writer can present a completed script(s) it makes you look more professional than the next writer to approach the artist and it gives the artist an idea of what the story will be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Schedules.
Once you and the artist either agree on a collaboration agreement or a work for hire agreement find out the artist or writer&amp;#8217;s REALISTIC schedule for turning in pages.
Once you&amp;#8217;ve got an idea then create a calendar and count lets say two days for every page.
This gives you a bit of cushion when it comes to the production of the pages and says that you&amp;#8217;re considerate of the artist&amp;#8217;s time.
You can add or subtract days but it should all depend on the agreement between you and your co-conspirators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building your artistic team.
While the artist is working to draw up character designs, layout of pages, and finally do penciling duties you as the creator should be out busting your ass to complete your artistic team.
Namely, we&amp;#8217;re talking about acquiring an inker, (which depending on the project can be optional) colorist, letterer, and possibly a graphic designer.
These positions mean just as much as the penciler and writer, if not more, in the production of the comic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Production schedule.
Now that the pencils are starting to flow in you as the creator should create a production schedule in which you know exactly where the production of the book is.
By this I mean that if pencil pages 1-5 have come in and you&amp;#8217;re awaiting pages 5-10 then pages 1-5 should be with the inker, then to the colorist, and on to the letterer until they&amp;#8217;re finished.
The more you can keep the machine oiled and running the better for you because one never knows when life may shut down your production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game time.
Now that you&amp;#8217;ve got your first issue done, sit it to the side for about a week or two.
In that time give your team that time to rejuvenate if you feel that you all have been burning the candle at both ends.
After the timeout open the files for the first issue, print them out and go through every page with a red pen, looking for grammatical errors that may have shown up in the first past.
Once you&amp;#8217;ve proofed the book and you feel that it&amp;#8217;s in the best shape possible then file it away and begin work on the next issue.
Yep, you heard me right.
No, you&amp;#8217;re not going to release the first issue.
Why?
Because you want at least 3-4 issues of not more under your belt before you start to distribute the book just in case life should get in the way of production of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you follow these steps you&amp;#8217;ll save yourself a headache or two.
In the next post I&amp;#8217;ll try to get a little more in-depth about the production of the comic when you start to involve the inker, colorist, letterer, and graphic designers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_discussion&#34;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One Response to “Writing for the love of it. #2”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[quote,Posted by Ted Bergeron | February 15, 2012, 4:52 pm
&lt;em&gt;__&lt;/em&gt;]
That is pretty comprehensive!
That&amp;#8217;s a good point about having 3 or 4 issues done before distributing.
That way you could keep the momentum going and retain readers by meeting a release schedule.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Writing for the love of it. #1</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2012-01-18-Writing-for-the-love-of-it-1/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2012 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2012-01-18-Writing-for-the-love-of-it-1/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_blog&#34;&gt;Blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By Alverne Ball&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;ve been trying to think about what to write for this blog, which I have no name for, wait, I think I just discovered what it&amp;#8217;ll be called.
 How about &#34;writing for the love of it&#34;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So that&amp;#8217;s what this blog is going to be called and since this is the first of what I hope will be many let&amp;#8217;s start with the inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re going to write comics then you have to first write for the love of it. 
I&amp;#8217;m sure you&amp;#8217;ve heard this many times before and from better writers with accolades that far outweigh mine. 
But it&amp;#8217;s the truth. 
If you&amp;#8217;re going to write comic books then you have to right for the love of it because most of the time that&amp;#8217;s all you&amp;#8217;re going to get from it, along with the occasional headache when you&amp;#8217;re trying to put together a creative team, but that&amp;#8217;s a subject for a different time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;#8217;ve got the essential theme of this here blog out of the way let&amp;#8217;s get down to the reason of how to write comics books. 
When I started out there wasn&amp;#8217;t as much information about writing comics as there is now.  
But I always advise new writers to take an art class on making comics. 
That&amp;#8217;s what I did when I was in high school. 
Took an after school class on how to draw and make comics. 
Don&amp;#8217;t think for one minute that I can draw. 
I can&amp;#8217;t even draw straight stick figures. 
But I took the drawing class so that I could better understand what artists were seeing when I tried writing a script. 
The art class also taught me about spatial relationships between objects, which is something that I also picked up from my fiction writing classes at Columbia College Chicago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I&amp;#8217;d advise would be to read both volumes of writers on comic scriptwriting.
(&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.com/184023069X&#34;&gt;http://amzn.com/184023069X&lt;/a&gt;) 
These two volumes are full of great writing samples from some the best in the business. 
It&amp;#8217;s a great tool for figuring out one&amp;#8217;s writing style, which in some cases can also help you figure out your writer&amp;#8217;s voice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another great source for reading and some great examples of storytelling would be Dwayne McDuffie&amp;#8217;s website &lt;a href=&#34;http://dwaynemcduffie.com&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;http://dwaynemcduffie.com&lt;/a&gt;
(which I cannot lie I hadn&amp;#8217;t enjoyed until he was gone)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These few resources should be enough to get any young writer on his/ her way towards writing comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week I&amp;#8217;ll try to cover the beginning: from idea to the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_discussion&#34;&gt;Discussion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No comments yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
