<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indie Comics Group | making and sharing comics </title>
    <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/tags/comic-books/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author></author>
    <rights>(C) 2013</rights>
    <updated>2012-04-15 11:30:20 &#43;0200 &#43;0200</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Copyright</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2012-04-15-Copyright/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 15 Apr 2012 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2012-04-15-Copyright/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Ted Bergeron ⋅ April 15, 2012 ⋅ Post a comment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;I am not a lawyer&#34;, but here&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;ve heard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the USA as soon as you create a work, it is yours and generally accepted that you are reserving your rights.
Place &#34;© 2012 Your Name&#34; on your work to give notice of your copyright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past a strategy was to send a copy of your work to yourself via registered mail and never open the envelope until you needed to defend your copyright in a court of law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My understanding is that by registering your copyright with the US Government, all you are doing is creating an official time-stamp on your work.
That date that you registered your work will have a greater legal weight in a court of law.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But here&amp;#8217;s the kicker.
Your copyright notice and whether or not you have registered it with the US Government does not prevent anyone from stealing your work.
What it does to is enable you to defend your rights in a court of law.
You still have to hire a lawyer and go to court and take the proper steps to get the thief to cease and desist and more action to sue them for damages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can send in a whole stack of your comics and copyright the whole lot with one $35 registration fee.
So if it gives you peace of mind, it&amp;#8217;s pretty cheap.
And it&amp;#8217;s kinda cool to get a copy of your registration back from the government with their stamp on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;more info: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.copyright.gov/help/faq/&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;http://www.copyright.gov/help/faq/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m making comics for fun and just want to share them.
I would be upset if someone stole my characters and tried to profit from them.
But I&amp;#8217;m not worried about it.
I&amp;#8217;d be flattered if someone made some fan art using them!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_just_sketch_your_own_characters&#34;&gt;Just sketch your own characters&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that Disney has acquired Marvel, the Disney lawyers are going around comic cons and slapping cease and desist on any artist that is trying to sell sketches of Marvel characters for money.
So some of the voices in the industry are saying, &#39;just sketch your own characters&#39; … I think that is a great idea.
I think it mostly concerns famous artists that formerly worked for Marvel and fans know them for their work on those Marvel characters…
and they don&amp;#8217;t have any original characters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Digital Publishing and Distribution</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2012-03-21-Digital-publishing-and-distributing/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 21 Mar 2012 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2012-03-21-Digital-publishing-and-distributing/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital Publishing and Distribution&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By Ted Bergeron ⋅ March 21, 2012 ⋅ Post a comment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m very interested in this topic but I think it&amp;#8217;s confusing because you have&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&#34;Printing&#34; aspect; Digital formatting of your book to work on various e-readers, tablets, laptops and phones.
I think this conversion process could be compared to a printing company creating a book.
I&amp;#8217;ve dabbled with this creating .pdf, ePUB and Kindle formats, but I haven&amp;#8217;t really tested on anything other than my laptop.
My point is it can be done with time, talent, and a computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Distribution… that is tricky.
It would be great if once you had all your digital formats (files and apps) you could ship these off the &#34;comic book stores&#34;.
But in reality you have to get into the proprietary distribution pipelines like Amazon Kindle or Apple iTunes, Graphicly, Comixology, Diamond Digital  …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sales… Generally speaking you could sell your own digital comics off your own website with a simple PayPal button and attach a PDF file and e-mail the customer.
I don&amp;#8217;t know if you can even get a Kindle book or iTunes app without going through their pipeline?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m keeping an eye on this new store front: &lt;a href=&#34;http://indyplanet.com/digital/&#34; class=&#34;bare&#34;&gt;http://indyplanet.com/digital/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_we_need_an_open_universal_format&#34;&gt;We Need an Open, Universal Format&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From an indie perspective, I&amp;#8217;d like to see us all agree on a universal open format (like ePUB or is there something better?) that works on almost most every electronic device and forget the color tablet wars that are competing for consumers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Share this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;•Share
•&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discussion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No comments yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>Preparing for Free Comic Book Day</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-15-Preparing-for-Free-Comic-Book-Day/</link>
          <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2011 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-15-Preparing-for-Free-Comic-Book-Day/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;sect1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;_fcbd&#34;&gt;FCBD&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sectionbody&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Well 2012 is nearly here and already the big publishers have got their &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comicsbeat.com/2011/12/09/full-line-up-of-2012-free-comic-book-day-books-announced&#34;&gt;full line up&lt;/a&gt;
for &lt;a href=&#34;http://freecomicbookday.com&#34;&gt;Free Comic Book Day&lt;/a&gt; coming up Saturday May, 5th 2012.
This got me thinking, what&amp;#8217;s stopping us Indie Comics makers from promoting our books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we got together and each submitted 4 to 8 pages each, then grouped the pages by genre.
We could print our own books and give them away at local comic book shops.
Each creator could pitch in and share the cost.
If four makers contributed 6 pages and cover, you&amp;#8217;d could sell 2 full page ads from other indie comic book makers plus the back page.
That makes a 28 page book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;admonitionblock tip&#34;&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fa icon-tip&#34; title=&#34;Tip&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td class=&#34;content&#34;&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborate together to create an anthology.
Share the cost of printing.
Sell ads for other Indie Comic Books of a similar genre.&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you targeted the comic book shops just in your area.
This could really open the doors for you to get your books on their shelves.
Especially if customers came back asking for your works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m sure there are some pros and cons to this approach.
I&amp;#8217;d welcome your comments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Future of Publishing</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-11-The-Future-of-Publishing/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2011 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-11-The-Future-of-Publishing/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;sect2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;_by_ted_bergeron&#34;&gt;By Ted Bergeron&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m trying to imagine what the future of comics will be.
So I&amp;#8217;m trying to create a &#39;blueprint&#39; for making comics so that they still could be printed.
Then take those files and make mobile apps, color e-books, web comics… every method of sharing comics digitally.
The idea is books could be printed, if anyone wanted to pay a lot for one, but mostly they&amp;#8217;d be shared electronically.
I think this would be the most inexpensive method for indie creators to share their work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m firmly in the paper book camp.
But I&amp;#8217;m trying to embrace the migration to mostly electronic for comics.
I&amp;#8217;m predicting the future is digital with a handful of lovingly crafted, print-on-demand comics (probably collected works / graphic novels) for collectors that treasure a particular comic book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;sect3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;_comments&#34;&gt;Comments&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-quote-left fa-1x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
Howdy, I do think your website may be having internet browser compatibility problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whenever I take a look at your website in Safari, it looks fine but when opening in IE, it has some overlapping issues.
I merely wanted to provide you with a quick heads up!
Besides that, great website!
&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-quote-right fa-1x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;
&amp;#8212; Posted by Mississauga Soccer | August 5&lt;br&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;2013&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;ulist&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reply to this comment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;quoteblock&#34;&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-quote-left fa-1x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ll take a look. And thanks for checking out the website.
&lt;span class=&#34;icon&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-quote-right fa-1x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;attribution&#34;&gt;
&amp;#8212; Posted by Ted Bergeron | August 6&lt;br&gt;
&lt;cite&gt;2013&lt;/cite&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Way Forward</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-07-The-Way-Forward/</link>
          <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2011 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-07-The-Way-Forward/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If we all work together we can achieve our dreams.
So step one has to be what are our dreams?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As creators, I think we all want to work on making comics full time.
So my first thought is why don&amp;#8217;t I get a job as a comic book artist?
Well, easier said than done.
So I need to build a portfolio.
Make some comics.
Start showing off my work.
Start knocking on big publisher&amp;#8217;s doors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stepping back I realized that since I was already making comics, just for the fun of it.
I might be able to short cut the process and just publish them myself.
So I started off shrinking down my full size comic book pages to fit into a mini comic book.
5-1/2 x 8-1/2 folded and stapled and &#39;printed&#39; B&amp;amp;W on a photocopier.
That is a fairly simple and inexpensive method of printing a comic book.
And I was able to put my comic book into the reader&amp;#8217;s hands.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I made my black and white art to the correct size, I can still have it colored and send it of to the printer to have them make some color glossy comic books for me.
I&amp;#8217;d still have to invest my money into printing these, but I&amp;#8217;d have them on hand to sell at conventions or off my website.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next I looked into making a digital copy.
It was fairly easy to make a .PDF file that I could e-mail to people.
And I can make as many copies as I need for free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m happy to share what I know with anyone that is making comics.
So I intend to start adding some tutorials in the wiki.
If you&amp;#8217;d like to share your knowledge, please join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    
      
        <item>
          <title>The Beginning</title>
          <link>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-06-The-Beginning/</link>
          <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2011 11:30:20 &#43;0200</pubDate>
          <author></author>
          <guid>http://indiecomicsgroup.org/post/2011-12-06-The-Beginning/</guid>
          <description>&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the beginning.
I&amp;#8217;ve created this website with the intention of helping others make comics and share comics.
I teach a making comic books class at my local Community College.
I find that many people have a desire to create stories but not very many people know what all goes into making comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After they&amp;#8217;ve made some comics the next question is usually how do I get published?
Which generally translates into how do I become rich and famous making comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;paragraph&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are going to attempt to answer these questions here and share some guidelines and standards.
Hopefully we will all learn something and together become the largest voice in comics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
